## Jesús Rincón Gallegos

2790 Kelvin Ave. Apt. 1131. Irvine, CA 92614.

Mobile: 949-668-3309

E-mail: jrg27s@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Worked in the Technician/support business for Hewlett-Packard products, for 7 years of experience. I am an entrepreneur in business leadership and management. Worked Developed strong communication and management skills. Able to work under pressure as well as learn and adapt quickly to new work environments. Ambitious and enthusiastic, seeking a career opportunity to continue developing interpersonal and technical skills in electronics and customer service.

## **EDUCATION**

Aug. 2009 – May 2013. Universidad Autónoma de Ciudad Juárez (UACJ). Juarez City, Chihuahua.

Bachelor of Arts, Visual Arts: Painting, Sculpture, Photography and Video.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hewlett-Packard ASC (Authorized Service Center): Informática Administrativa del Norte.

## May 2016 - Jan 2020 Manager.

Promoted to manager to administrate activities in two cities Tijuana and Mexicali, Baja California, Mexico. Responsible of:

- Hiring and managing staff. Interview and train new employees for a fast paced, customer service environment.
- Administrate priorities and activities of works orders based on each technician's experience and certificates obtained by training.
- Creation of "work routes" to minimize vehicle usage and gas expenses.
- Weekly reports to review expenses, creation of new routes and lessons learned on how the most critical issues were solved with less effort and costs.

#### April 2013 – May 2016. HP Technician.

Diagnostic and repair of electronic equipment (HP products) such as industrial printers, computers, and laptops. Recognized as one of the 20 best technicians of the Hewlett-Packard ASC companies in Mexico.

- Installation and configuration of equipment (Pinter, computer, DesignJet) in the network using DHCP and static
- Installation and configuration of equipment (Pinter, computer, DesignJet) with windows 7, Windows 8.1 and Windows 10
- Install operating systems and software like Windows 7,8.1,10 and Office.
- Knowledge in imaging using Ghost, Acronis, clonezilla

## Jan 2013 – April 2013 HP Operator.

Visual inspection of electronic equipment. Usage of web servers to evaluate product status for troubleshooting.

### **COURSES**

All the courses are provided and certificated by HP (Hewlett Packard) more than 50 certificates because of the variety of equipment.

- ESD (Electrostatic Discharge).
- HP equipment repair: Computer, Laptops, RPOS (Point of Sales), Printers, DesignJet.
- HP software and tools for evaluation and diagnosis.
- IT essentials by Cisco Networking Academy
- CNNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to Networks by Cisco Networking Academy

# **SKILLS**

- Leadership.
- Team work.
- Communication.
- Staff management.

## KNOWN LANGUAGES

- Spanish native speaking
- English.
- 50% LSM (Mexican Sign Language)

- Planning.
- Decision Making.
- Troubleshooting.